<resources>
    <string name="app_name">test</string>
    <string name="a_human_memory_education_and_rehabilitation_tool">A Human Memory education and rehabilitation tool</string>

    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="welcome_to_muscle_memory_a_human_memory_education_and_rehabilitation_tool_this_application_will_provide_you_with_information_and_education_on_the_subject_of_human_memory_there_will_also_be_games_and_quizzes_that_will_help_enhance_your_memory">Welcome to Muscle Memory - A Human Memory education and rehabilitation tool! This application will provide you with information and education on the subject of human memory. There will also be games and quizzes that will help enhance your memory!</string>
    <string name="this_application_will_also_help_you_with_day_to_day_activities_such_as_setting_reminders_for_events_using_a_digital_calendar_and_resources_to_learn_more_about_strategies_to_protect_you_from_cognitive_decline">This application will also help you with day to day activities, such as setting reminders for events, using a digital calendar and resources to learn more about strategies to protect you from cognitive decline</string>
    <string name="muscle_memory">Muscle Memory</string>

    <string name="go_back">Go Back</string>

    <string name="moreInfo">This application was made as part of a Computer Science and Software Engineering final year project. It should not be used to diagnose any memory problems. If you are worried about any memory related issues, please contact your GP. The information used in this application is verified by evidence based research.</string>

    <string name="learnMore">If you feel you are struggling with memory related issues, you should contact your GP at the earliest convenience. There are many resources online available that you can make use of, such as https://alzheimer.ie/get-support/resources-and-factsheets/ https://www.understandtogether.ie/  and https://www.alz.org/help-support/caregiving</string>

    <string name="tip1">Get a large wall calendar and hang it up in a prominent place at home. Get in a routine of adding appointments, birthdays etc.. on a daily basis!</string>
    <string name="tip2">Be sure to get at least 7 hours sleep! Sleep helps in recalling facts and information as well as in procedural memory formation - the aspect of memory involved in learning new skills faster.</string>
    <string name="tip3">Have a card in your work area with a simple message on it like "Focus on what to do!" This can help you to avoid drifting off </string>
    <string name="tip4">If you feel that you are being overloaded - especially in a conversation with someone, ask the person to slow down with the information or repeat what they have said.</string>
    <string name="tip5">Work at your best time - work at the time of day when you are most alert and focused (For most people, this is the morning!)</string>

    <string-array name="tipsy">
        <item>Get a large wall calendar and hang it up in a prominent place at home. Get in a routine of adding appointments, birthdays etc.. on a daily basis!</item>
        <item>Be sure to get at least 7 hours sleep! Sleep helps in recalling facts and information as well as in procedural memory formation - the aspect of memory involved in learning new skills faster.</item>
        <item>Have a card in your work area with a simple message on it like "Focus on what to do!" This can help you to avoid drifting off.</item>
        <item>If you feel that you are being overloaded - especially in a conversation with someone, ask the person to slow down with the information or repeat what they have said.</item>
        <item>Work at your best time - work at the time of day when you are most alert and focused (For most people, this is the morning!)</item>
        <item>If you are worried that you will not be able to know todays date when you are checking the calendar, you can also get in the habit of ticking off the day that has just been completed on your calendar before you go to bed.</item>
        <item>Try to work in a quiet environment with no background distractions, such as noisy televisions or people talking. This will help improve your concentration.</item>
        <item>Let people know they should try not to interrupt you when you are working. This will help improve your concentration.</item>
        <item>Take frequent breaks! If the problem is made worse by fatigue, work for shorter periods of time. Periods up to 30 minutes tend to be more productive.</item>
        <item>Talk to yourself - Saying things out loud, like "What should I be doing now? or "Stay focused!" can help yourself to stay on the right track. </item>
        <item>Concentrate on one thing at a time - taking in or trying to do too many things at once leads to mistakes. Do one thing well, then move on to the next thing.</item>
        <item>Do not rush things - Take your time and pace yourself. Rushing leads to mistakes!</item>
        <item>Make a plan - keep a record - or break things down into manageable parts. If you do get distracted, you can easily pick up from where you left off if you have organisation and structure.</item>
        <item>Check and double check your work. It will be slow and hard at first, but it will become a habit as you get accustomed to it. This is the only sure-fire way of picking up on your own errors.</item>
        <item>Listen really attentively to the headlines on the news and see how much of the details you can really absorb accurately and then relay back to others - Test yourself each day!</item>
        <item>When taking a telephone message, listen carefully to the person giving the message, repeat the message with the person on the other end of the phone and write it down as soon as possible!</item>
        <item>When asking for directions, listen carefully to the person giving directions - also watch carefully if they are pointing in order to recall the directions. Confirm the directions with the person.</item>
        <item>Repeat information over and over, silently in your mind.</item>
        <item>Try to attach new information to existing memories - it helps to process the new information more deeply.</item>
        <item>Have a key ring by the door where you always hang your keys.</item>
        <item>Have a special place to keep your wallet and glasses.</item>
        <item>Have a filing system for bills and legal documents, and a tray for bills and letters!</item>
        <item>Place items strategically e.g put letters that you plan to post by the front door.</item>
        <item>Set up electronic reminders! For instance, you can create email or text alerts to signal it is time to take your medicine.</item>
        <item>Make a link of taking whatever medication you may take with an activity you do every day, such as making coffee or brushing your teeth. This works much better than taking medication in the midst of other activities.</item>
        <item>Setting a daily alarm can be helpful, especially if you struggle with timing requirements.</item>
        <item>Make a point of noticing when you take your medication. For instance, before taking your pill, pause, look at it in your hand, and tell yourself that you are taking the pill now. You will have a specific memory trace to todays dose.</item>
        <item>If you are just starting your medication, leave it out in an easy to spot space.</item>
        <item>When attending an appointment place your bag in front of you rather thank behind you to prevent forgetting it.</item>
        <item>Make lists! such as shopping lists, or lists to help organize the day.</item>
        <item>Have reminder notes in the kitchen, such as turn off the cooker or put away the milk!</item>
        <item>Write on the back of your hand - just a letter of the alphabet can often be enough to trigger you to remember something important you meant to do.</item>
        <item>Make ip a story or rhyme that contains information that you want to remember.</item>
        <item>Repeat the information in your mind immediately after you have taken it in - test yourself after a slight delay - increase the delay by a few hours - test yourself after a few days.</item>
        <item>Adapt your environment - keep a notepad and pen by the telephone, put up a notice board and label cupboards and doors.</item>
        <item>It is important to reduce anxiety, stress and depression - they make memory difficulties worse. Talk about your difficulties to friends and family.</item>
        <item>Put effort into maintaining friendships and developing new friendships.</item>


    </string-array>


    <string-array name="attention1">
        <item>Attention is the basis of all new learning and memory.</item>
        <item>Attention generally explains our ability to focus and hold attention on words on a page, a conversation, music, or traffic on the road when we are driving.</item>
        <item>People with attention problems often complain that they can no longer concentrate on reading books, do tasks and maintain a conversation at the same time, or they may have difficulty studying for any length of time.</item>
        <item>Attention helps us to select specific information and decide what information is important and what is not.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="attention2">
        <item>There are different types of attention: </item>
        <item>Focused attention - Our ability to respond immediately to a stimulus - e.g. turning your head when someone calls your name, fixing your gaze on something interesting (e.g. a street performer among a busy crowd).</item>
        <item>Sustained attention - Our capacity to maintain our focus on specific stimuli - e.g. listening carefully to a telephone message or to a lecture.</item>
        <item>Selective attention - Our ability to filter out distractions and select important information - e.g. listening out for our flight details in the airport, whilst filtering out all the other announcements and distractions in the busy airport.</item>
        <item>Divided Attention - The ability to pay attention to two or more things at the same time e.g. watching the news on TV, whilst knitting and keeping and eye on the children playing on the floor. Or speaking on the phone, whilst typing and listening to music in the background.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="attention3">
        <item>There are many ways of improving attention and concentration:</item>
        <item>Minimise Distractions - Try to work in a quiet environment with no background distractions, such as noisy televisions or people talking. Let people know they should try to not interrupt you when you are working.</item>
        <item>Take Frequent Breaks - If the problem is made worse by fatigue, work for shorter periods of time and take breaks. Periods for up to 30 minutes tend to be more productive.</item>
        <item>Talk to yourself and say things out loud - Say things like \"What should I be doing now?\" or \"Stay focused!\" can help yourself to stay on the right track.</item>
        <item>Use Cue Cards - Have a card in your work area with a simple message on it \"FOCUS ON WHAT TO DO!\" This can help you to avoid drifting off. Or a little alarm on your phone or watch can be set to go off and remind you to stay focused.</item>
        <item>Set Yourself targets or goals - It is easier to stay motivated if you have a goal or target to work towards - if the goal is too easy set yourself harder ones.</item>
        <item>Use incentives - Reward yourself! If you manage to achieve your goals - treat yourself to a reward.</item>
        <item>Be assertive and Gain Control - If you feel that you are being overloaded - especially in a conversation with someone, ask the person to slow down with the information or repeat what they have said e.g \"Excuse me, I think you have lost me, could you repeat that?\"</item>
        <item>Work at your best time - work at the time of day when you are most alert and focused (For most people, this is the morning!)</item>
        <item>Do one thing at a time - Concentrate on one thing at a time - taking in or trying to do too many things at once leads to mistakes. Do one thing well, then move on to the next thing.</item>
        <item>Do not rush things - Take your time and pace yourself - rushing leads to mistakes.</item>
        <item>Apply Structure and Routine - Make a plan or break things down into manageable parts. If you do get distracted, you can easily pick up from where you left off if you have organisation and structure.</item>
        <item>Check and Double check your work - Do this with everything you do. It will be slow and hard at first, but it will become a habit as you get accustomed to it. This is the only sure fire way of picking up on your own errors.</item>
        <item>Listen really attentively to the headlines on the news (on the radio and TV) and see how much of the details you can really absorb accurately and then relay back to others. Test yourself every day.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="attention4">
        <item>Learning to use a notebook or memory book:</item>
        <item>Portable with a pen - A small portable book is best for people who are mobile and on the go!</item>
        <item>Personalised book - when you buy a book, take out any sections that are not relevant to you.</item>
        <item>Emphasise the importance - if you cannot see the importance in using it, you probably will not use it. Identify three reasons why the book is important and write it on the inside page to remind you why it is going to be helpful to you.</item>
        <item>Train yourself to use the book - Initially this may just mean learning to carry it around wherever you go, as if it is part of your brain. Once this habit is established, practice finding each section in the book until you can do it easily and quickly.</item>
        <item>Look at it regularly! This is the most important thing, you need to look at it regularly.</item>
        <item>A typical memory book will contain the following sections: A daily schedule to keep track of the things that you should be doing, A reference section for telephone numbers and addresses, and a notes section to write notes and to-do lists.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shortTerm1">
        <item>Short-term memory is the capacity to take in and hold information for a very short period of time from a few seconds to a couple of minutes.</item>
        <item>It is a very temporary store. The information is either lost, or stored in the long term memory.</item>
        <item>This type of memory is used to look up a phone number in the telephone dictionary. You might repeat the number a few times until you dial the number. Once you have used the number it is either forgotten - or you might learn it and use it in the future.</item>
        <item>We have the choice to store information for longer in our long term memory stores - or if not important, we can let it fade away.</item>
        <item>As short term memory is a temporary store - the person often has to be able to remember the information \"There and then\".</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shortTerm2">
        <item>When taking a telephone message:</item>
        <item>1. Listen Carefully to the person giving the message.</item>
        <item>2. Repeat or confirm the message with the person on the other end of the phone.</item>
        <item>3. Pass the message on or write it down as soon as possible.</item>
        <item> --- </item>
        <item>When asking for directions:</item>
        <item>1. Listen carefully to the person giving the directions - also watching carefully if they are pointing in order to recall the directions.</item>
        <item>2. Repeat or confirm the directions with the person to help encode the information.</item>
        <item>3. We tend to use this information immediately. Depending on how important it is to us, we either forget it as soon as we have found our destination - or store it in our long term memory.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shortTerm3">
        <item>These are the things you do \"inside your head\" to try to remember things.</item>
        <item>ATTENTION - Pay attention, focus on what is being said, and try to reduce background distractions.</item>
        <item>SMALL CHUNKS - Break down information into small, relevant, simple chunks. Put no more than 5 to 6 bits of information in each category.</item>
        <item>REPEAT AND REHEARSE - Repeat information over and over, silently in your mind .. a useful way to remember a name or telephone number.</item>
        <item>AIM FOR \"DEEP LEVEL PROCESSING\" - Try to attach new information to existing memories - it helps to process the new information more deeply.</item>
        <item>MAKE LINKS OR ASSOCIATIONS - e.g. if you want to remember that Mary\'s birthday is the 27th December - imagine that 2 days after Christmas - poor Mary probably got lots of joint presents as a child! Sometimes the more bizarre the association, the better we remember it.</item>
        <item>MAKE VISUAL PICTURES - \"A picture is worth a thousand words\". We remember pictures and images much more than words. If you have to remember a name - think of names in terms of a picture to help to remember it.</item>
        <item>ASK YOURSELF QUESTIONS - THE FIVE W\'s : \"Who?\" \"What?\" \"Where?\" \"Why?\" and \"When?\". This is helpful in trying to remember a newspaper article or story.</item>
        <item>STORIES OR RHYMES - Make up a story or rhyme that contains information that you want to remember. E.g. F(Face) A(Arm) S(Speech) T(Time) - Stroke FAST Campaign.</item>
        <item>ERRORLESS LEARNING - Get it right the first time!</item>
        <item>EXPANDED REHEARSAL - Repeat the information in your mind immediately after you have taken it in - test yourself after a slight delay - increase the delay by a few hours - test yourself after a few days.</item>
        <item>RETRACE BY USING RETRIEVAL CUES - Retrace a sequence of events and actions in your mind in order to remember something - mentally retrace your steps. This is a good method if you are trying to remember where you have put something.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="longTerm1">
        <item>Long term memory is the brain\'s way of storing information so it can be used later. It includes big pieces of information, like:</item>
        <item>Things you learned as a child (How to play the piano, build a sand castle, make a cake, how to change a tyre)</item>
        <item>Events that happened in your life (Your first day at school or college and everyday events like recalling what you ate for breakfast yesterday morning)</item>
        <item>There are no known limits on the amount of information that can be stored in long term memory</item>
        <item> </item>
        <item>What types of information are kept in long term memory?</item>
        <item>Episodic information which is the stories or episodes of our lives.</item>
        <item>Factual information and general knowledge: e.g the grass is green and Dublin is the capital of Ireland.</item>
        <item>Procedural information: This involves remembering how to do things without having to think about how to do it. For example getting dressed, driving a car or typing.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="longTerm2">
        <item>Here are some tips for remembering to take any medications or tablets you may need to take!</item>
        <item>1. Use a pillbox - The best and easiest strategy is to put your medication in a weekly pillbox that has a compartment for each day. It doesn\'t just visually remind you to take your medication but also prevents double doses. Fill your pillbox with any medications, supplements or vitamins your doctor has prescribed. The pharmacist can plan out your medications in a \"Blister Pack\" in this way.</item>
        <item>2. Take advantage of technology - Set up electronic reminders. For instance, you can create email or text alerts to signal it\'s time to take your medicine.</item>
        <item>3. Combine with a daily task - Make a link of taking your medication with an activity you do every day, such as making coffee or brushing your teeth. This works much better than taking the medication at a free floating time or in the midst of other variable activities.</item>
        <item>4. Set an Alarm - Setting a daily alarm can be helpful, especially if the timing requirements for when you are supposed to take it tend to be tighter.</item>
        <item>5. Break out of autopilot - Make a point of noticing when you take your medication. For instance, before taking your pill, pause, look at it in your hand, and tell yourself: \"I\'m taking Tuesday\'s pill now\". This makes it more likely that you will have a specific memory traced for today\'s dose.</item>
        <item>6. Keep it visible - \"Out of sight, out of mind!\" So if you\'re just starting your medication, leave it out in an easy to spot place.</item>
        <item>7. Enlist a loved one\'s help - It can help to have a non judgemental, positive person who understands your situation to support you through your treatment. This person can help you remember to take your medicine.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="longTerm3">
        <item>Here are some strategies to help improve your long term wellbeing..</item>
        <item>Get into a routine! Routines and good habits can ease memory difficulties. Pay bills on time if possible and set up standing orders for bills. Carry out certain activities on certain days and keep a daily timetable on the notice board - and USE IT!</item>
        <item>Improve your wellbeing - It is important to reduce anxiety, stress and depression - they make memory difficulties worse. Talk about your difficulties to friends and family. Put effort into maintaining friendships and developing new friendships.</item>
        <item>Seek out relaxing pleasurable activities - learn to relax and look after yourself. stay physically active and fit - exercise at least once a day.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="prospective1">
        <item>Prospective memory is the ability to remember things for the future. It is strongly linked to long term memory and the ability to plan and organise. Prospective memory refers to remembering to perform intended actions in the future, or simply, \"remembering to remember\"</item>
        <item>Examples of Prospective Memory include remembering to take medicine at night before going to bed, remembering to deliver a message to a friend, and remembering to pick up flowers for a significant other on an anniversary. It may be either event based or time based and is often triggered by a cue.</item>
        <item>Event based Prospective Memory involves remembering to do a certain action when the specific circumstances are present. For example, driving past the local library cues you to remember that you need to return an overdue book.</item>
        <item>Time based Prospective Memory involves remembering to do an action at a particular point in time. For example, seeing that it is 10 pm acts as a cue for you to know that it is time to watch your favourite television show.</item>
        <item>Prospective memory is useful for remembering appointments, planning and organising our time, remembering to take medications and remembering important events e.g. birthdays.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="prospective2">
        <item>Use a calendar - with a friend or family member write your appointment onto the calendar and make checking the calendar part of your daily routine. Friends and family members may have to prompt you to make this part of your daily routine.</item>
        <item>Use an alarm system - If your medications need to be taken at the same time daily, set an alarm for this time. ALSO, if you don\'t have an alarm that tells you what you are supposed to remember, have a pnote beside the alarm telling you why the alarm is going off.</item>
        <item>Use post it\'s or a memo board - just make sure that it does not get too cluttered! Do it as soon as you think of it or write it down and leave it somewhere where you will spot it again within a reasonable time frame.</item>
        <item>Keep a notebook and pen either on you or in your bag, beside the phone, at the front door and don\'t forget to check it regularly!</item>
        <item>Positioning - place letters for posting by the door as a visual reminder to post them when you\'re going into town. When attending an appointment place your items in front of you rather than behind you to prevent forgetting it.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="prospective3">
        <item>Telephone answering machines - Reduces the problem of phone messages being forgotten or lost.</item>
        <item>Make Lists - Shopping lists, or lists to help organise the day.</item>
        <item>Use a pill reminder for medication - Get into the routine of filling the pill planner before you go to bed each night - or on a Sunday night for use throughout the week. Keep the pill planner in a very obvious place. The pharmacist can organise all the pills in a blister pack for the week.</item>
        <item>Keep a kitchen timer by the cooker: Alarms are useful reminders to start or stop a certain activity.</item>
        <item>List telephone numbers - Keep a list of important telephone numbers by the phone - or put numbers on \"Speed Dial\" on your phone and mobile phone. The name and number can also have a small photograph of the person you mean to ring.</item>
        <item>Computers - They can be very good for storing information if you have an interest in using computers.</item>
        <item>Reminder notes - \"Turn off the cooker\", \"Remeber keys\", \"Lock the front door\". Laminated signs over the cooker, at the front door etc.</item>
        <item>Write on the back of your hand - Just a letter of the alphabet can often be enough to trigger you to remember something important you mean to do.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="inext1">
        <item>Here are some External Memory Strategies - These are things like taking notes, keeping a diary, using a calendar or just getting into a regular routine.</item>
        <item>Adapt your environment - Keep a notepad and pen by the phone, put up a notice board or white board and label cupboards.</item>
        <item>A place for everything and everything in its place - Have a jey ring by the door where you always hang your keys, a special place to keep your wallet and glasses, have an \"In Tray\" for bills and letters, have a filing system for bills, and place items strategically e.g put letters that you plan to post by the front door.</item>
        <item>Getting into a routine - Routines and good habits can ease memory difficulties. Pay bills on time if possible and set up direct debits for bills. Carry out certain activities on certain days and keep a daily timetable on a notice board.</item>
        <item>Improve your wellbeing - It is important to reduce anxiety, stress and depression - they make memory difficulties worse. Talk about your difficulties to friends and family. Put effort into maintaining friendships and developing new friendships.</item>
        <item>Seek out relaxing pleasurable activities - learn to relax and look after yourself. stay physically active and fit - exercise at least once a day.</item>
        <item>Learn to say \"No\" to excessive demands and manage your time efficiently - Take breaks.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="inext2">
        <item>Portable Diary or Filofax notebook - Keep a larger diary at home to record the events of the day.</item>
        <item>Use \"Post-it\" stickers - put a sticker on each day of your diary with a \"to do\" list on it.</item>
        <item>White board - use it for reminders of events and messages and to help to plan.</item>
        <item>Calendar - It is useful for writing down appointments and social occasions.</item>
        <item>Watch - Use a battery operated watch that can bleep to give you a hourly prompt to check your daily planner.</item>
        <item>Dictaphone - Record verbal messages.</item>
        <item>Use a pill reminder for medication - Get into the routine of filling the pill planner before you go to bed each night - or on a Sunday night for use throughout the week. Keep the pill planner in a very obvious place. The pharmacist can organise all the pills in a blister pack for the week.</item>
        <item>Keep a kitchen timer by the cooker: Alarms are useful reminders to start or stop a certain activity.</item>
        <item>Computers - They can be very good for storing information if you have an interest in using computers.</item>
        <item>Reminder notes - \"Turn off the cooker\", \"Remeber keys\", \"Lock the front door\". Laminated signs over the cooker, at the front door etc.</item>
        <item>Write on the back of your hand - Just a letter of the alphabet can often be enough to trigger you to remember something important you mean to do.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
