<resources>
    <string name="app_name">test</string>
    <string name="a_human_memory_education_and_rehabilitation_tool">A Human Memory education and rehabilitation tool</string>

    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="welcome_to_muscle_memory_a_human_memory_education_and_rehabilitation_tool_this_application_will_provide_you_with_information_and_education_on_the_subject_of_human_memory_there_will_also_be_games_and_quizzes_that_will_help_enhance_your_memory">Welcome to Muscle Memory - A Human Memory education and rehabilitation tool! This application will provide you with information and education on the subject of human memory. There will also be games and quizzes that will help enhance your memory!</string>
    <string name="this_application_will_also_help_you_with_day_to_day_activities_such_as_setting_reminders_for_events_using_a_digital_calendar_and_resources_to_learn_more_about_strategies_to_protect_you_from_cognitive_decline">This application will also help you with day to day activities, such as setting reminders for events, using a digital calendar and resources to learn more about strategies to protect you from cognitive decline</string>
    <string name="muscle_memory">Muscle Memory</string>

    <string name="go_back">Go Back</string>


    <string name="tip1">Get a large wall calendar and hang it up in a prominent place at home. Get in a routine of adding appointments, birthdays etc.. on a daily basis!</string>
    <string name="tip2">Be sure to get at least 7 hours sleep! Sleep helps in recalling facts and information as well as in procedural memory formation - the aspect of memory involved in learning new skills faster.</string>
    <string name="tip3">Have a card in your work area with a simple message on it like "Focus on what to do!" This can help you to avoid drifting off </string>
    <string name="tip4">If you feel that you are being overloaded - especially in a conversation with someone, ask the person to slow down with the information or repeat what they have said.</string>
    <string name="tip5">Work at your best time - work at the time of day when you are most alert and focused (For most people, this is the morning!)</string>

    <string-array name="tipsy">
        <item>Get a large wall calendar and hang it up in a prominent place at home. Get in a routine of adding appointments, birthdays etc.. on a daily basis!</item>
        <item>Be sure to get at least 7 hours sleep! Sleep helps in recalling facts and information as well as in procedural memory formation - the aspect of memory involved in learning new skills faster.</item>
        <item>Have a card in your work area with a simple message on it like "Focus on what to do!" This can help you to avoid drifting off.</item>
        <item>If you feel that you are being overloaded - especially in a conversation with someone, ask the person to slow down with the information or repeat what they have said.</item>
        <item>Work at your best time - work at the time of day when you are most alert and focused (For most people, this is the morning!)</item>
        <item>If you are worried that you will not be able to know todays date when you are checking the calendar, you can also get in the habit of ticking off the day that has just been completed on your calendar before you go to bed.</item>
        <item>Try to work in a quiet environment with no background distractions, such as noisy televisions or people talking. This will help improve your concentration.</item>
        <item>Let people know they should try not to interrupt you when you are working. This will help improve your concentration.</item>
        <item>Take frequent breaks! If the problem is made worse by fatigue, work for shorter periods of time. Periods up to 30 minutes tend to be more productive.</item>
        <item>Talk to yourself - Saying things out loud, like "What should I be doing now? or "Stay focused!" can help yourself to stay on the right track. </item>
        <item>Concentrate on one thing at a time - taking in or trying to do too many things at once leads to mistakes. Do one thing well, then move on to the next thing.</item>
        <item>Do not rush things - Take your time and pace yourself. Rushing leads to mistakes!</item>
        <item>Make a plan - keep a record - or break things down into manageable parts. If you do get distracted, you can easily pick up from where you left off if you have organisation and structure.</item>
        <item>Check and double check your work. It will be slow and hard at first, but it will become a habit as you get accustomed to it. This is the only sure-fire way of picking up on your own errors.</item>
        <item>Listen really attentively to the headlines on the news and see how much of the details you can really absorb accurately and then relay back to others - Test yourself each day!</item>
        <item>When taking a telephone message, listen carefully to the person giving the message, repeat the message with the person on the other end of the phone and write it down as soon as possible!</item>
        <item>When asking for directions, listen carefully to the person giving directions - also watch carefully if they are pointing in order to recall the directions. Confirm the directions with the person.</item>
        <item>Im on pg 36</item>

    </string-array>


</resources>
